# JAMES ELMS

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT
07413627372
james_elms@live.co.uk
www.elms64.github.io
Bordon, Hampshire UK
SKILLS
.NET Development
Database Design and Management
Full-Stack Web Development
UI and UX Design
EDUCATION
BSc Computing with Software Engineering
BSc Computing with Software Engineering University of Surrey
University of Surrey
University of Surrey 2021-2024 Predicted Grade - 1:1
University of Surrey  2021-2024  Predicted Grade - 1:1 Studied at University Centre Farnborough Graphic Design, Information Technology
University of Surrey  2021-2024  Predicted Grade - 1:1 Studied at University Centre Farnborough  Graphic Design, Information Technology and Business Studies
University of Surrey  2021-2024  Predicted Grade - 1:1 Studied at University Centre Farnborough  Graphic Design, Information Technology and Business Studies  Alton College
University of Surrey  2021-2024  Predicted Grade - 1:1 Studied at University Centre Farnborough  Graphic Design, Information Technology and Business Studies  Alton College  2016-2018
University of Surrey  2021-2024  Predicted Grade - 1:1 Studied at University Centre Farnborough  Graphic Design, Information Technology and Business Studies  Alton College  2016-2018  A Levels
University of Surrey  2021-2024  Predicted Grade - 1:1 Studied at University Centre Farnborough  Graphic Design, Information Technology and Business Studies  Alton College  2016-2018  A Levels

12 GCSE's at C and above.

#### PROFILE

I have completed a BSc in Computing, due to graduate this October with a predicted 1:1, and I am looking to work with a company whom I can build upon my existing and learned skills. I have been awarded Student of the Year three years running as recognition of my achievements and so far, I have consistently achieved the highest grade boundary in every topic studied.

I started retraining in my mid-twenties and prior to this I had a career as a horticulturist in team leader roles, spanning over a few years, as well as having experience in office-based environments as a young adult.

I have had the opportunity to design, create and deploy a fully functional inventory management and booking software system, commissioned by the university's media department which has been a huge success thus far. The application system allows students to view and book media equipment, as well as allowing teachers to seamlessly manage these loans and the overall inventory and system of users. I used the identity framework and Graph API to integrate authentication into the existing Microsoft Entra tenant for the college and deployed the web application using Azure App Service. I am competent with these technologies and I am looking forward to exploring a career in .NET development.

In addition to this I have completed several software development projects using C# and I am competent in ASP.NET, EF Core, Razor Pages, Git / GitHub, SQL, HTML CSS and JS. I have gained valuable experience in software development, in addition to my time spent in other industries prior to my study and I am very keen to start the next phase. I am a very hardworking and reliable person with great initiative skills and instinct. I am looking forward to working in a team and utilising my excellent interpersonal communication skills. I am adaptable and flexible in any environment and possess the ability to make crucial decisions with quick timing, understanding cause and effect within a working environment and applying this to many diverse settings. I excel at building long-lasting rapport with both colleagues and clients, leveraging the strengths of my team and myself to continually advance our professional development.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

### Freelance Full-Stack Software Developer

Self Employed

January 2024 to Present

- I have had the opportunity to begin my software development career whilst in
  my final year at university, working on both front-end and back-end technologies.
   Currently, I am working on building a new website for a pre-school and I am in
  contact with some other prospective clients for web based projects.
- I have also had the opportunity to work with the Media department at Farnborough College of Technology to design an inventory management system that allows them to manage student loans for camera equipment. It replaces an existing legacy system of paper documents and excel spreadsheets into a reliable web application with role based access for students and teachers. Students can book equipment and check item availability ahead of time using either the mobile or desktop site. The system was built using ASP.NET Razor Pages, Identity platform and several other frameworks and technologies. I am in the process of assisting with the official deployment of this solution into the college network over the summer, using Azure App Service for a cloud-based architecture.

# JAMES ELMS

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

### CERTIFICATIONS

#### Networking

Enterprise Networking, Security and Automation CCNA v7.0

Advanced Routing and Switching CCNA v7.0

Introduction to Networks CCNA v7.0

Cisco CyberOps Associate

### **Horticulture and Grounds Maintenance**

PA1 / PA6: Safe Application of Pesticides

Level 2 Certificate in Practical Horticulture (RHS)

### TECHNOLOGIES

I have used and am competent with the following development technologies:

























## REFERENCES

## Gbenga Ogunduyile

01252 405555

g.ogunduyile@farn-ct.ac.uk

#### **Emil Naydenov**

01252 405555

e.naydenov@farn-ct.ac.uk

#### **Horticulturist**

Self Employed

May 2017 to September 2021

During this time I worked with multiple sole traders, larger companies and my own clients on a range of projects in horticulture, landscape gardening, lawn care and other aspects of grounds maintenance. One notable company I worked with was Bath & North East Somerset Council, where I had the opportunity to take part on award winning horticulture projects in the city of Bath.

In this role I have been responsible for my own clients, work and equipment managing my own time and sub contracting to other businesses, building long standing relationships and establishing a presence for myself and my trade in the local area. I have managed sites and been responsible for other workers as a supervisor or foreman on several occasions.

### **Supervisor**

Get Fresh and Fruity (Alton, Hampshire)

October 2016 to May 2017

In this role I started as a customer service assistant and was promoted to supervisor. My responsibilities were:

- · Answering the phone
- · Stock counting
- · Picking / packing orders
- · Closing / opening store
- Money handling
- Operating tills / customer service
- · Delegating jobs to other members of staff
- Ensuring shift runs smoothly

## **Previous Work Experience**

Various Roles 2014 - 2016

During this period, I explored various entry-level positions in customer service and office-based roles. I gained valuable experience in:

- Customer Service: Worked independently and as part of a team to assist customers, resolving issues and providing high-quality service.
- Office Administration: Developed a good understanding of business operations, including data entry, scheduling, and administrative support.
- Team Collaboration: Collaborated effectively with colleagues, enhancing team productivity and contributing to a positive work environment.